<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Release on open62541</title><link>https://open62541.github.io/open62541-www/tags/release/</link><description>Recent content in Release on open62541</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://open62541.github.io/open62541-www/tags/release/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Release: open62541 Version 1.3</title><link>https://open62541.github.io/open62541-www/blog/release-1-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open62541.github.io/open62541-www/blog/release-1-3/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Release notes Version 1.3:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first release of the 1.3 release series of open62541.
Going forward, only fixes and non-breaking changes will be integrated in the 1.3 release family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="new-features-compared-to-the-previous-release-series-12-include"&gt;New features compared to the previous release series 1.2 include:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for OPC UA PubSub encryption (also TPM-based key handling)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Session authentication with x509 certificates (server-side)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for Event Filters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for Server Diagnostics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Binary/JSON encoding as a stable public API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Handling of Subscriptions with different priority&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Greatly improved Nodeset Compiler, including support for structure values&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added UA_order function for all data types (equality test / absolute ordering for binary search trees, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for TLS-encrypted MQTT-based PubSub&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internally generate temporary self-signed certificates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides the major functional additions, many small features, fixes and general improvements went into this release. Particularly, the memory consumption of the information model was reduced by about 1/3 compared to the 1.2 release series.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Release: open62541 Version 1.2.3</title><link>https://open62541.github.io/open62541-www/blog/release-1-2-3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open62541.github.io/open62541-www/blog/release-1-2-3/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Release notes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the third patch release for the 1.2 release family of open62541.
There were only bugfixes and no API-breaking changes applied for the patch release.
Important changes compared to the previous release include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(plugin): Remove assert about the key length in ua_openssl_basic256sha256.c&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(arch): Use AF_INET in the socket hints if IPV6 is disabled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(arch) : ServerNetworkLayerTCP_start continues if one network interface fails to bind&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(pubsub): Allow multiple readers on the same NetworkMessage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;open62541 (&lt;a href="http://open62541.org"&gt;http://open62541.org&lt;/a&gt;) is an open source and free implementation of OPC UA (OPC Unified Architecture) written in the common subset of the C99 and C++98 languages. The library is usable with all major compilers and provides the necessary tools to implement dedicated OPC UA clients and servers, or to integrate OPC UA-based communication into existing applications. The open62541 library is platform independent. All platform-specific functionality is implemented via exchangeable plugins. Plugin implementations are provided for the major operating systems.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>