<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Osadl on open62541</title><link>https://www.open62541.org/tags/osadl/</link><description>Recent content in Osadl on open62541</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.open62541.org/tags/osadl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Workshop on 'OPC UA with open62541' took place</title><link>https://www.open62541.org/blog/osadl-workshop-2023/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.open62541.org/blog/osadl-workshop-2023/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Workshop OPC UA with open62541&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of November, the first OPC UA workshop in collaboration of &lt;a href="https://www.iosb.fraunhofer.de/de/kompetenzen/systemtechnik/kognitive-industrielle-systeme.html"&gt;Fraunhofer IOSB&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.osadl.org/"&gt;OSADL&lt;/a&gt; took place. The two-day online workshop was fully booked after a short time and more than 50 participants attended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the presentation and hands-on sessions by Fraunhofer and OSADL, a keynote address was given by Mr. Alexander Allmendinger from the OPC Foundation European Certification Lab on the topic &amp;lsquo;OPC UA - THE solution for Industry 4.0 and IIoT&amp;rsquo;. The sessions in the workshop covered the topics OPC UA, open62541 and open source development. The OPC UA track focused on specification and information modeling. The open62541 content ranged from the development of simple client-server applications to advanced build configurations and use of PubSub. The track on open source development was devoted to the development process and licensing issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Announcement - OSADL LoI Phase #4</title><link>https://www.open62541.org/blog/osadl-loi-phase-4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.open62541.org/blog/osadl-loi-phase-4/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OSADL LoI Project #4:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might be aware of the past &amp;ldquo;Letter of Intent&amp;rdquo; (LoI) projects done for open62541 in the framework of the OSADL (Open Source in Automation Development Labs). Companies can sign the Letter of Intent with their level of desired contribution and the project starts when a threshold is crossed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The LoI projects have a well-defined scope in terms of content and timeline. They are used for a targeted &amp;ldquo;push&amp;rdquo; which could not be covered by the steady pace of development in the community. For example, PubSub communication was developed in the earlier LoI projects.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>