<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Community on open62541</title><link>https://www.open62541.org/categories/community/</link><description>Recent content in Community on open62541</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.open62541.org/categories/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Announcement - OSADL LoI Phase #4</title><link>https://www.open62541.org/blog/osadl-loi-phase-4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.open62541.org/blog/osadl-loi-phase-4/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OSADL LoI Project #4:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might be aware of the past &amp;ldquo;Letter of Intent&amp;rdquo; (LoI) projects done for open62541 in the framework of the OSADL (Open Source in Automation Development Labs). Companies can sign the Letter of Intent with their level of desired contribution and the project starts when a threshold is crossed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The LoI projects have a well-defined scope in terms of content and timeline. They are used for a targeted &amp;ldquo;push&amp;rdquo; which could not be covered by the steady pace of development in the community. For example, PubSub communication was developed in the earlier LoI projects.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>June 2022 Community Newsletter</title><link>https://www.open62541.org/blog/newsletter-june-2022/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.open62541.org/blog/newsletter-june-2022/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="open62541--hannover-fair"&gt;open62541 @ Hannover Fair&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year did we again present open62541 at the Hannover Fair.
See below the &amp;ldquo;partner pod&amp;rdquo; at the booth of the OPC Foundation.
It was great connecting with the community directly after two years of remote work.
Thanks also to OSADL and Kalycito for co-organizing the booth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Andreas Ebner (left) and Julius Pfrommer (right) at Hannover Fair 2022)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="new-open62541-website--interview-with-götz-görisch"&gt;New open62541 Website – Interview with Götz Görisch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new open62541-website is now finally online!
We also started to publish articles and news on the new website.
Make sure you read the great interview with Götz Görisch from the VDW – Verein Deutscher Werkzeugmaschinenfabriken e.V.
&lt;a href="https://www.open62541.org/blog/vdw-interview"&gt;Link to the Interview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Interview with Götz Görisch from the VDW</title><link>https://www.open62541.org/blog/vdw-interview/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.open62541.org/blog/vdw-interview/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="1-who-are-you-and-what-is-your-role-at-vdw"&gt;1. Who are you and what is your role at VDW?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, my name is Götz Görisch. I work at the German Machine Tool Builders` Association (VDW – Verein Deutscher Werkzeugmaschinenfabriken e.V.) as the expert for digitization and open interfaces. I am the elected chairperson for the &amp;ldquo;OPC UA for Machine Tools joint working group&amp;rdquo; with the OPC Foundation. In this position I&amp;rsquo;m leading the companion spec work for OPC 40501 (UA4MT) and 40502 (UA4CNC). Additional I&amp;rsquo;m an &amp;ldquo;umati evangelist&amp;rdquo; for the umati community to drive the adoption of OPC UA in the machine building industries.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>