<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on open62541</title><link>https://www.open62541.org/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on open62541</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.open62541.org/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Developer training for OPC UA and open62541</title><link>https://www.open62541.org/blog/developer-training-2025/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.open62541.org/blog/developer-training-2025/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;✨ Developer training for OPC UA and open62541: Your key to industrial communication! ✨&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take part in our three day OPC UA training and learn from the main developers of the open62541 OPC UA library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this workshop you will be introduced to the basics and advanced concepts of OPC UA. You will get a practical look at the architecture and structure of the OPC UA specification, the security mechanisms as well as the modeling and implementation of information models. Participants will develop applications using the open source open62541 library and learn the correct usage of the library as well as background information about the implementation from the main developers.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>open62541 @ Hannover Fair 2023</title><link>https://www.open62541.org/blog/hmi-2023-video/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.open62541.org/blog/hmi-2023-video/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The open62541 project exhibited again this year at the booth of the OPC Foundation on the Hannover Fair 23. The organization and representation of the project was done by Dr. Julius Pfrommer and Andreas Ebner from Fraunhofer IOSB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the following video, Dr. Julius Pfrommer talks about news and updates from the open62541 project. The video was recorded at our booth at the Hannover Fair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in further news and would like to meet us in person at the next trade show, please subscribe to the mailing list &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/g/open62541"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Workshop on 'OPC UA with open62541' took place</title><link>https://www.open62541.org/blog/osadl-workshop-2023/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.open62541.org/blog/osadl-workshop-2023/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Workshop OPC UA with open62541&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of November, the first OPC UA workshop in collaboration of &lt;a href="https://www.iosb.fraunhofer.de/de/kompetenzen/systemtechnik/kognitive-industrielle-systeme.html"&gt;Fraunhofer IOSB&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.osadl.org/"&gt;OSADL&lt;/a&gt; took place. The two-day online workshop was fully booked after a short time and more than 50 participants attended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the presentation and hands-on sessions by Fraunhofer and OSADL, a keynote address was given by Mr. Alexander Allmendinger from the OPC Foundation European Certification Lab on the topic &amp;lsquo;OPC UA - THE solution for Industry 4.0 and IIoT&amp;rsquo;. The sessions in the workshop covered the topics OPC UA, open62541 and open source development. The OPC UA track focused on specification and information modeling. The open62541 content ranged from the development of simple client-server applications to advanced build configurations and use of PubSub. The track on open source development was devoted to the development process and licensing issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Announcement - OSADL LoI Phase #4</title><link>https://www.open62541.org/blog/osadl-loi-phase-4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.open62541.org/blog/osadl-loi-phase-4/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OSADL LoI Project #4:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might be aware of the past &amp;ldquo;Letter of Intent&amp;rdquo; (LoI) projects done for open62541 in the framework of the OSADL (Open Source in Automation Development Labs). Companies can sign the Letter of Intent with their level of desired contribution and the project starts when a threshold is crossed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The LoI projects have a well-defined scope in terms of content and timeline. They are used for a targeted &amp;ldquo;push&amp;rdquo; which could not be covered by the steady pace of development in the community. For example, PubSub communication was developed in the earlier LoI projects.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>June 2022 Community Newsletter</title><link>https://www.open62541.org/blog/newsletter-june-2022/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.open62541.org/blog/newsletter-june-2022/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="open62541--hannover-fair"&gt;open62541 @ Hannover Fair&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year did we again present open62541 at the Hannover Fair.
See below the &amp;ldquo;partner pod&amp;rdquo; at the booth of the OPC Foundation.
It was great connecting with the community directly after two years of remote work.
Thanks also to OSADL and Kalycito for co-organizing the booth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Andreas Ebner (left) and Julius Pfrommer (right) at Hannover Fair 2022)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="new-open62541-website--interview-with-götz-görisch"&gt;New open62541 Website – Interview with Götz Görisch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new open62541-website is now finally online!
We also started to publish articles and news on the new website.
Make sure you read the great interview with Götz Görisch from the VDW – Verein Deutscher Werkzeugmaschinenfabriken e.V.
&lt;a href="https://www.open62541.org/blog/vdw-interview"&gt;Link to the Interview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Interview with Götz Görisch from the VDW</title><link>https://www.open62541.org/blog/vdw-interview/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.open62541.org/blog/vdw-interview/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="1-who-are-you-and-what-is-your-role-at-vdw"&gt;1. Who are you and what is your role at VDW?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, my name is Götz Görisch. I work at the German Machine Tool Builders` Association (VDW – Verein Deutscher Werkzeugmaschinenfabriken e.V.) as the expert for digitization and open interfaces. I am the elected chairperson for the &amp;ldquo;OPC UA for Machine Tools joint working group&amp;rdquo; with the OPC Foundation. In this position I&amp;rsquo;m leading the companion spec work for OPC 40501 (UA4MT) and 40502 (UA4CNC). Additional I&amp;rsquo;m an &amp;ldquo;umati evangelist&amp;rdquo; for the umati community to drive the adoption of OPC UA in the machine building industries.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Release: open62541 Version 1.3</title><link>https://www.open62541.org/blog/release-1-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.open62541.org/blog/release-1-3/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Release notes Version 1.3:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first release of the 1.3 release series of open62541.
Going forward, only fixes and non-breaking changes will be integrated in the 1.3 release family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="new-features-compared-to-the-previous-release-series-12-include"&gt;New features compared to the previous release series 1.2 include:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for OPC UA PubSub encryption (also TPM-based key handling)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Session authentication with x509 certificates (server-side)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for Event Filters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for Server Diagnostics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Binary/JSON encoding as a stable public API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Handling of Subscriptions with different priority&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Greatly improved Nodeset Compiler, including support for structure values&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added UA_order function for all data types (equality test / absolute ordering for binary search trees, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for TLS-encrypted MQTT-based PubSub&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internally generate temporary self-signed certificates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides the major functional additions, many small features, fixes and general improvements went into this release. Particularly, the memory consumption of the information model was reduced by about 1/3 compared to the 1.2 release series.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Feature Spotlight: Pretty-printing in the gdb Debugger</title><link>https://www.open62541.org/blog/pretty-printing-gdb/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.open62541.org/blog/pretty-printing-gdb/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A little known feature that adds a lot of convenience for developers on Linux is the pretty-printing of OPC UA data types. It reduces visual noise and makes the introspection of local variables much more convenient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pretty-printing can be activated by loading the definitions as &lt;code&gt;source &amp;lt;open62541&amp;gt;/tools/gdb-pretty-print.py&lt;/code&gt;.
Below are some before/after examples to showcase the effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="nodeids"&gt;NodeIds&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NodeIds have four different representations (numeric, string, guid, bytestring).
This leads to a very cluttered gdb output due to the C-union where a numeric id is also interpreted as a (string) pointer.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Release: open62541 Version 1.2.3</title><link>https://www.open62541.org/blog/release-1-2-3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.open62541.org/blog/release-1-2-3/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Release notes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the third patch release for the 1.2 release family of open62541.
There were only bugfixes and no API-breaking changes applied for the patch release.
Important changes compared to the previous release include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(plugin): Remove assert about the key length in ua_openssl_basic256sha256.c&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(arch): Use AF_INET in the socket hints if IPV6 is disabled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(arch) : ServerNetworkLayerTCP_start continues if one network interface fails to bind&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fix(pubsub): Allow multiple readers on the same NetworkMessage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;open62541 (&lt;a href="http://open62541.org"&gt;http://open62541.org&lt;/a&gt;) is an open source and free implementation of OPC UA (OPC Unified Architecture) written in the common subset of the C99 and C++98 languages. The library is usable with all major compilers and provides the necessary tools to implement dedicated OPC UA clients and servers, or to integrate OPC UA-based communication into existing applications. The open62541 library is platform independent. All platform-specific functionality is implemented via exchangeable plugins. Plugin implementations are provided for the major operating systems.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Announcement: New Website for the open62541 project</title><link>https://www.open62541.org/blog/new-website/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.open62541.org/blog/new-website/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The open62541 has now a new modern website. The website is built with the HUGO Framework (&lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/"&gt;https://gohugo.io/&lt;/a&gt;) and the content is therefore completely written in markdown. The website is public visible in our open62541-www repository. The deploy process of the new webpage is automated by a github action. During the deploy phase the markdown files are compiled with the hugo tools to a static website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New responsive design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Secure static website&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publicly visible in the open62541-www repository&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>