<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Workshop on open62541</title><link>https://open62541.github.io/open62541-www/tags/workshop/</link><description>Recent content in Workshop on open62541</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://open62541.github.io/open62541-www/tags/workshop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Developer training for OPC UA and open62541</title><link>https://open62541.github.io/open62541-www/blog/developer-training-2025/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open62541.github.io/open62541-www/blog/developer-training-2025/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;✨ Developer training for OPC UA and open62541: Your key to industrial communication! ✨&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take part in our three day OPC UA training and learn from the main developers of the open62541 OPC UA library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this workshop you will be introduced to the basics and advanced concepts of OPC UA. You will get a practical look at the architecture and structure of the OPC UA specification, the security mechanisms as well as the modeling and implementation of information models. Participants will develop applications using the open source open62541 library and learn the correct usage of the library as well as background information about the implementation from the main developers.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Workshop on 'OPC UA with open62541' took place</title><link>https://open62541.github.io/open62541-www/blog/osadl-workshop-2023/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open62541.github.io/open62541-www/blog/osadl-workshop-2023/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Workshop OPC UA with open62541&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of November, the first OPC UA workshop in collaboration of &lt;a href="https://www.iosb.fraunhofer.de/de/kompetenzen/systemtechnik/kognitive-industrielle-systeme.html"&gt;Fraunhofer IOSB&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.osadl.org/"&gt;OSADL&lt;/a&gt; took place. The two-day online workshop was fully booked after a short time and more than 50 participants attended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the presentation and hands-on sessions by Fraunhofer and OSADL, a keynote address was given by Mr. Alexander Allmendinger from the OPC Foundation European Certification Lab on the topic &amp;lsquo;OPC UA - THE solution for Industry 4.0 and IIoT&amp;rsquo;. The sessions in the workshop covered the topics OPC UA, open62541 and open source development. The OPC UA track focused on specification and information modeling. The open62541 content ranged from the development of simple client-server applications to advanced build configurations and use of PubSub. The track on open source development was devoted to the development process and licensing issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>